ADEYEMI, SEGUN AYODEJI

SUMMARY

Frontend developer (React and React Native) with a track record of working well with backend devs. Taking on extra responsibilities when necessary and working closely with team members to ensure workloads are efficiently directed to bottlenecks, with love for both software development and personal development. I have over four or more years of experience, I have honed my skills in Frontend Development and UI/UX Design with lots of achievements and work well in a team with an outstanding technical skills.

EDUCATION

B.Tech Computer Science & Engineering | Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Ogbomoso. Oyo State. Nigeria

FEBRUARY 2016 - APRIL 2022.

Senior Secondary School Certificate Examination | Saint Kizito's Catholic College, Ikirun. Osun State. Nigeria

SEPTEMBER 2009 - JULY 2012.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND DEVELOPER CONTRACT (REMOTE) | Softhood Technologies, Abuja. Nigeria OCTOBER 2022 - CURRENT.

- Developed full-stack web application that takes twitter tweet link and convert the tweet into a video either in mp4 or gif.
- Used Next JS for frontend development.
- Worked closely with the backend developer.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs, and enhancements.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER INTERN | SQI College of ICT, Ogbomoso. Oyo State. Nigeria SEPTEMBER 2020 - JULY 2021.

- Acquire knowledge of software engineering best practices.
- Wrote clear, clean and optimize code for various software frontend development project using REACT JS, VUE and ANGULAR JS.
- Accumulated in-depth understanding of changing technological developments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML CSS JAVASCRIPT TAILWINDCSS TYPESCRIPT REACT JS
- NEXT JS
 REACT NATIVE
 UI/UX DESIGN
 RESTAPI
 CONTEXT API
 REDUX
- MONGODB
 NODE JS
 MYSQL
 EXPRESS

SOFT SKILLS

- GOOD COMMUNICATION TEAM WORK CREATIVITY PROBLEM SOLVING
- TIME MANAGEMENT
 OPEN TO IMPORVEMENT AND LEARNING

PROJECTS

TWEETCLIPS | Next JS

- A web based application that is capable of converting twitter tweet using the tweet link into a mp4 video or gif with custom background design, font and so on.
- Implements users login and registration using traditional process and social means, with JWT Authentication for users login.
- Incorporate remotion library for video and gif generation.
- Ability for users to be able to connect their social account to the application for easy upload of the video or gif generated on their social media accounts.
- Built with tailwindcss and react framer motion for nice interface and awesome user experience.
- Uses FORMIK for all form validations, so as to ease form submission process.
- All state are being manage using CONTEXT API with useReducer.
- Implement RESTAPI for all CRUD operations with JWT verification.

Project Link - https://tweetclips.io

ESTASHUP | React JS (TypeScript) & Node JS

- A thrift web app that allows registered users to perform thrift contribution and also simulate a personal wallet that can be fund within the app.
- Registered user can create a stash group with a unique group code or group link generated that can be use to invite other users to join the group.
- All the state in the app are being manage using REDUX.
- User can join and also check group using the group link or group code before joining the group.
- Implement RESTAPI for all CRUD operations with JWT verification.
- Uses JWT Authentication for users login, creating group, join group and other actions by user.
- Uses FORMIK for all form validations, so as to ease form submission process.

Project Link - http://estashup.netlify.app/

TODO APP | React JS (TypeScript)

- A project to design a web based todo application, in which the user can create a list of todo task the user plans to achieve and can edit and also mark each todo has completed when its done.
- Optimized Typescript Code.

Project Link - https://todo-typescriptreact.netlify.app/

PORTFOLIO LINKS

- Github https://github.com/AyodejiSheen
- Behance https://behance.net/ayodejisegun
- Personal Website https://ayodejh.netlify.app